Hey, everyone.
We're back for another Fader video.
And this one is all about the
Fader page UI.
A s I mentioned in the last video,
just like the sequence series,
these videos come with a Capture
and a Blackout file, so you can download
those and play around with some lights
without having to set anything up.
Check out that other video if you haven't
already, and let's get into it.
Before we dive into this video,
I want to get philosophical for a second,
because one of the most common
questions I get asked is
What do I use a fader for?
Do I have a fader for all of my fixtures?
Do I make a fader for every parameter
possible and control everything that way?
And something that really helped me
understand this is the use of the word
handle.
A lot of programmers
will call faders handles,
and the idea is when you make a fader,
you're making something
that you can grab at an instant.
So if you're just doing
a super simple commercial
or narrative shoot
and you're just setting levels
and making them into looks,
you probably don't need any faders.
But a fader is really useful for something
that you might need at any moment
to change - like a light on the camera,
where it’s moving back and forth from talent
and you want to ride that level regardless
of what you've recorded into the look.
You want to override that with a fader.
That's a great use for a fader.
So start thinking about faders as handles,
things that you can grab at any time
because the order might change.
And we all know in the film industry
that's always happening.
So I'm always putting hazers on a fader
because I'm hazing at random moments
and I don't want to record that
into my looks.
I'm putting effects on faders.
I'm putting my battery units on faders
so I can change all of that at a moment's
notice, regardless of what I recorded.
We'll talk about this
more in future videos.
I just wanted to say that
since it comes up so often.